NullInjectorError: No provider\h for the injectable class.\h
NullInjectorError: No provider\h for the injectable class.\h
You'll encounter this error when\h you attempt to inject a service,\h\h
當你嘗試注入一個服務，卻沒有宣告對應的提供者時 就會遇到本錯誤
without declaring the corresponding provider. In other words, your code is attempting to use\h\h
換句話說，你的程式碼嘗試使用某個依賴
a dependency, but Angular has no way to find\h or inject that dependency, because there is\h\h
但是 Angular 卻無法找到或注入那個依賴
currently no provider pointing to it. But what is a provider exactly?\h\h
因為目前沒有任何提供者指向它 但所謂的“提供者”到底是什麼呢？
Think of it like a prescription for a medication,\h where the prescription is a provider and the\h\h
你可以把它看一個藥物的處方，這個“處方”就是提供者
medication is an injectable service. What the\h error is telling us is that we're trying to\h\h
而這個藥物就是用於注入的服務。本錯誤告訴我們的是
use a medication that has not been prescribed.\h There are two places we can address the issue:\h\h
我們正試圖使用一種沒有處方的藥物 可以用兩種方式解決此問題：
the injectable decorator or the provider's array\h in an ngModule. In either case, a provider is\h\h
@Injectable 裝飾器，或者在 ngModule 的 providers 陣列中 無論哪種方式，提供者都由三部分主要資訊構成
composed of three main pieces of information. First, it needs to know where to make the\h\h
首先，它需要知道在哪裡讓這個類可用
class available, like the root of\h the application or a feature module.\h\h
比如應用的根模組或特性模組
And second, it needs a token for locating that\h class within the dependency injection system. The\h\h
其次，它需要一個令牌（Token），以便在依賴注入體系中定位那個類
token is the class type that has been decorated.\h In most cases the token will be the same as the\h\h
這裡的令牌是一個帶有裝飾器的類別的型別 在多數情況下，此令牌和你要提供的類是同一個
class that you want to provide, however, it's\h possible to provide a third piece of information\h\h
不過，你還可以提供第三部分資訊，比如
like useClass to provide an entirely different\h class or useValue to provide a raw value.\h
用 useClass 來提供完全不同的一個類別，或者用 useValue 來提供一個原始值
Let's start by taking a look at a couple\h of common examples and quick fixes,\h\h
讓我們看一組常見的範例及其快速修復方式
then we'll take a more detailed look at\h injectors and providers to understand why\h\h
然後我們會深入看一下注入器和提供者，以便在更基礎的層面上
this error happens at a more fundamental level. In our code base we have a service decorated\h\h
理解為什麼會發生此錯誤 在我們的程式碼中，有一個帶有 @Injectable 裝飾器的服務
with @Injectable, but currently the service\h has not been provided to any ngModule within\h\h
但目前，該服務還沒有在應用內的任何 ngModule 中提供
the application. When we attempt to inject\h it in the constructor of the AppComponent,\h\h
當我們試圖在 AppComponent 的建構函式中中注入它時
the result is the NullInjectorError. The error\h message itself points to the offending class.\h\h
就會導致 NullInjectorError。此錯誤資訊指出了出錯的類
Now there are two main ways we might address the\h issue. If we want to provide the class throughout\h\h
現在，我們有兩種主要的方式解決此問題 如果我們要在整個應用範圍內提供這個類
the entire application we can use the providedIn:\h 'root' option. That'll provide a global singleton\h\h
可以使用 providedIn: 'root' 選項。它會提供一個全域單例
that can be used anywhere in the application\h and clears the error. However, that may not\h\h
此單例可以用於應用中的任何地方，並消除本錯誤
always be the optimal solution. In some cases,\h it may be more efficient to scope a service to\h\h
不過，這可能並不總是最合適的解決方案 某些情況下，更有效的方式是把某個服務侷限在某個特性模組內部
a feature module. And that can be achieved by\h providing an ngModule class as the providedIn\h\h
這可以透過把某個 ngModule 類作為 providedIn 選項的值來實現
option. That makes it possible to exclude this\h code from the app's main JavaScript bundle\h\h
這樣就讓我們可以從應用的主 JS 套件中排除這部分程式碼，按需延遲載入
and lazy load it when it becomes needed to improve\h load time performance. That's ideal when you have\h\h
這可以提升載入效能。當你有一個要在獨立模組中書踹死的服務時，這很好
a service that's used by an individual module,\h but what if a service is required by multiple lazy\h\h
但是如果該服務被多個延遲載入模組使用時怎麼辦呢？
loaded modules? In that case you may want each\h module to create its own instance of the service.\h\h
這種情況下，你可能希望每個模組都為本服務建立它自己的例項
That can be achieved with the providedIn:\h 'any' option. Instead of a singleton,\h\h
這可以透過 providedIn: 'any' 選項來實現
this option will instantiate a new service for\h each module that injects it. And one other option\h\h
這種方式下，服務不是單例的，而是為每個模組建立一個例項
to also be aware of is providedIn: 'platform',\h which is relevant to projects that use multiple\h\h
還有一個選項是 providedIn: 'platform'
Angular applications on a single page, such as\h web components with Angular elements for example.\h\h
它適用於那些要在同一個頁面中使用多個 Angular 應用的專案 比如透過 Angular Elements 實現的 Web Components
providedIn: 'platform' will make the service\h available to all applications on that page.\h
在同一個頁面中的所有 Angular 應用中可用
In total that's four different\h ways to provide a service.\h
總之，一共有四種不同的方式來提供某個服務
'root' instantiates a singleton\h for an entire Angular app,\h
'root' 會為整個 Angular 應用例項化一個單例
a module class provides a\h singleton for just that module,\h
“模組類”會單獨為那個模組提供一個單例
'any' provides an instance for\h each module that injects it,\h
'any' 會為每個注入它的模組提供一個例項
and 'platform' provides a singleton\h for multiple Angular applications.\h
而 'platform' 會為多個 Angular 應用提供一個單例
Now it's also worth noting that you can provide\h a service directly in the ngModule decorator.\h\h
另外，你還可以在 ngModule 裝飾器中直接提供某個服務
Import the service you want to provide then\h add it to the provider's array within the\h\h
只要匯入你要提供的服務 然後把它加到 ngModule 裝飾器的 providers 陣列中就可以了
ngModule decorator. This pattern also creates a\h provider, however it's generally not the preferred\h\h
這種模式也會建立一個提供者，不過通常不建議使用這種方式
approach because it makes the code more difficult\h to tree shake when a service has not been injected\h\h
因為它會讓這些程式碼在沒有任何地方注入它的時候，難以搖樹最佳化掉
anywhere. Now in many cases you may encounter the\h NullInjectorError from a third-party dependency\h\h
很多情況下，你可能遇到來自第三方依賴或
or one of Angular's built-in modules. For\h example, imagine we import the HTTP client into\h\h
比如，如果在 AppComponent 中匯入 HTTP Client，然後
our AppComponent, then inject it as a dependency\h in the constructor. That also throws an error,\h\h
把它注入為建構函式中的一個依賴項，同樣會丟擲一個錯誤
but you might be wondering why something built\h into Angular would not have a provider. There\h\h
但是你可能想不通為什麼 Angular 內建的東西還會沒有提供者
are only a handful of minimal services built into\h Angular core. Almost everything else is isolated\h\h
這是因為只有極少數服務才內建到了 Angular 核心中 其它的一切幾乎都拆到了自己的模組中
in its own module. What that means is that in\h order to use the HTTP client, we need to import\h\h
這意味著要使用 HTTP Client，我們就要
its corresponding ngModule in the module that\h depends on it, which in our case is the AppModule,\h\h
在依賴它的模組（AppModule）中匯入其對應的 ngModule
and we do that by adding it to its imports array.\h Now that we know how to fix the issue, let's talk\h\h
我們可以透過把它加入到 AppModule 的 imports 陣列中來實現 現在，我們知道了如何修復此錯誤，接下來我們談談注入器
about injectors. When Angular is bootstrapped, it\h creates an application-wide injector. Its job is\h\h
當 Angular 啟動時，它會建立一個全應用級注入器
to create and manage dependencies, and it does\h that by maintaining a collection of providers.\h\h
它的職責是建立和管理依賴，它會維護一個提供者的集合
Each provider contains a token or class type that\h tells Angular where to find the injectable value.\h\h
每個提供者具有一個令牌或類別的型別 它會告訴 Angular 去哪裡尋找要注入的值
In most cases a provider is created with\h the @Injectable decorator. When that class\h\h
大多數情況下，提供者是透過 @Injectable 裝飾器來建立的
is then referenced in the constructor of a\h component for example, the injector will use\h\h
比如當某個元件的建構函式中參考了這個類別的時候
the provider to find the existing instance of\h that class or instantiate a new one if required.\h\h
注入器就會使用此提供者來尋找該類別的現有例項，或者按需例項化一個新的
Every dependency needs to have at least one\h provider, and that brings us to the root of\h\h
每個依賴項都需要至少一個提供者，否則就會丟擲 NullInjectorError
the NullInjectorError. If there's no provider,\h it just doesn't work. Let's go ahead and recap.\h\h
如果沒有提供者，它就不能正常工作。我們來回顧一下
When you encounter the NullInjectorError, it\h means a service was injected without the necessary\h\h
當你遇到 NullInjectorError 時 它表示某個要注入的服務沒有必要的提供者
provider. The first step is to find the offending\h class. If it's one of your own injectable classes,\h\h
第一步是找到那個導致錯誤的類別。如果它是你自己的 @Injectable 類之一
you can provide it in the root of the application\h or provide it in an ngModule. If it's related to\h\h
你可以在應用的根或者某個 ngModule 中提供它
a third party dependency, you're likely\h missing an ngModule import. Determine\h\h
如果它和某個第三方依賴有關，可能是你忘了匯入某個 ngModule
where that service is provided, then import the\h corresponding ngModule. For additional details\h\h
你要找出那個服務是在哪裡提供的，然後匯入對應的 ngModule
and examples check out the dependency injection\h guide in the official Angular documentation
欲知詳情和範例，請閱讀Angular官方文件的“依賴注入”指南